Guide to the Maurice Durand Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Maurice Durand papers
1700-1966
MS 1728
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
36.25
(122 boxes)
The collection consists of publications, transliterations, photographs, research notes, and microfilm created, assembled, or used by Maurice Durand during his academic and administrative career. The material relates to Asia, primarily Vietnam, in the eighteenth, nineteenth, and twentieth centuries. Much of Durand's own research notes concern Vietnamese literature and Vietnamese and Indochinese linguistics. Durand was a well-known scholar of Han and Nom. Han is Chinese language texts written using Chinese characters. Nom is Vietnamese language texts written using Chinese characters. Many texts of the period in which Durand specialized are written in a mixture of Han and Nom.
Durand, Maurice M., 1966-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Southeast Asia Collection, 1996-1998, 2004-2005 and 2013.
Custodial History
The Southeast Asia Collection acquired this collection by purchase and donation from Mrs. Maurice Durand, 1967 and 1973. A portion of the collection was previously part of the Southeast Asia Collection (MS 743) in Manuscripts and Archives.
Existence and Location of Copies
Series I and Series II are available in digital form through the Yale University Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Series I and Series II have been digitized. Permission of the Librarian for Southeast Asian Studies is required for access to the original material.
Biographical / Historical
Maurice M. Durand (born 1914) was a prominent French scholar of Vietnam and China. He also served as director of the École française d'Extrême-Orient in Hanoi, Vietnam, and as director of the École Pratique des Hautes Études de la Sorbonne in Paris, France. Durand died on April 30, 1966.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of publications, transliterations, photographs, research notes, and microfilm created, assembled, or used by Maurice Durand during his academic and administrative career. The material relates to Asia, primarily Vietnam, in the eighteenth, nineteenth, and twentieth centuries. Much of Durand's own research notes concern Vietnamese literature and Vietnamese and Indochinese linguistics. Durand was a well-known scholar of Han and Nom. Han is Chinese language texts written using Chinese characters. Nom is Vietnamese language texts written using Chinese characters. Many texts of the period in which Durand specialized are written in a mixture of Han and Nom.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in five series: Series I. Han Nom Texts without Vietnamese, circa 1700-1900. Series II. Han Nom Texts with Vietnamese, circa 1700-1900. Series III. Visual Materials, circa 1950-circa 1959. Series IV. Research Notes, circa 1930-circa 1966. Series V. Microfilm, circa 1825-1955.
Hakka (Chinese people) -- Photographs; Hong Kong (China) -- Civilization -- 20th Century -- Photographs; Vietnam -- Literatures; Vietnam -- History; Vietnam; Durand, Maurice M., 1966-
- Han Nom texts without Vietnamese, Circa 1700-circa 1900; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of Han and Nom handwritten or woodblock texts without Vietnamese transliterations. They were reproduced from the École française d'Extrême-Orient in Paris. Exact dates for material in this series could not be determined.
  Conditions Governing Access
  The entire series has been digitized. Permission of the Librarian for Southeast Asian Studies is required for access to the original material.
  - Chinh Phụ Ngâm, Nôm (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Đại Việt Sử Kí Bản Kỉ Toàn Thư Quyển 1, Hán (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Đại Việt Sử Kí Bản Kỉ Toàn Thư Quyển 2, Hán (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Đại Việt Sử Kí Bản Kỉ Toàn Thực Quyển 15, Hán (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hàn Văn Thư Tích Tông Lục Thư Sách, Hán (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hoa Tiên Kí 2v., Hán (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hoàng Triều Châu Bản Mục Lục, Hán (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hoàng Việt Địa Dư Chí, Hán (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Kiến Văn Tiểu Lục, Hán (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Kiến Văn Tiểu Lục Quyển 2, Hán (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kiến Văn Tiểu Lục Quyển 4, Hán (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Kiến Văn Tiểu Lục Quyển 5, Hán (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Kiến Văn Tiểu Lục Quyển 6, Hán (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Kiến Văn Tiểu Lục Quyển 9, Hán (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Kiến Văn Tiểu Lục Quyển 10, Hán (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Kim Văn Kiều / Thanh Tâm Tài Tự Quyển 1, Hán (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Nguyễn Thị Tây Sơn Kí, Hán (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Tân Biên Truyền Kì Mạn Lục Quyển 1,Hán with Nôm annotations (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Tân Biên Truyền Kì Mạn Lục Quyển 2, Hán (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Tân Biên Truyền Kì Mạn Lục Quyển 3, Hán with Nôm annotations (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Tân Biên Truyền Kì Mạn Lục Quyển 4, Hán with Nôm annotations (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Tây Dương Liệt Phụ Truyện, Nôm (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Thạch Sanh Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Thiên Nam Dư Hạ Tập, Hán (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Trần Vương Truyện Khảo, Hán (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Trình Quốc Công Thi Tập, Nôm (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Vũ Trung Tùy Bút, Hán (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Nhị Độ Mai Tân Truyện, 1934 (Box 4A, Folder 28)
  - Kim Vân Kiều Tân Tập by Nguyễn Du (LXXVI), 1900s? (Box 4A, Folder 29)
  - Kim Vân Kiều Tân Tập by Nguyễn Du (LXXVII), 1900s? (Box 4A, Folder 30)
- Han Nom texts with Vietnamese, Circa 1700-circa 1900; Series II
  This series consists of Han and Nom handwritten texts in notebooks with Vietnamese transliterations. They were reproduced from the École française d'Extrême-Orient in Paris. Exact dates for the material in this series could not be determined.
  - Bài Văn Sách, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Chổng Mông Gào Chồng Phú (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Hà Thành Kỹ Nữ Oán Tứ (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Khêu Phòng Ngâm Khúc (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Thị Lựu Trần Tình Khúc (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Lẳng Lơ Phú (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Quá Xuân Nữ Phú (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Mẹ Ơi Con Muốn Lấy Chồng (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Thi Hỏng Tự Cười Mình Phú (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bài Văn Tế Trận Vong Tiến Sĩ (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bích Cau Ký Ngộ, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Chinh Phụ Ngâm (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Trường Hận Ca Diễn Âm (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ca Trù Thể Cách, Nôm (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chinh Phú Ngâm Bị Lục, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Chinh Phụ Tự Tình (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Chinh Phụ Từ (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bài Văn Tể Của Cự Phan Bộ Châu và Tể Cự Phan Chu Trinh (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Nam Nữ Đối Ca (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Vọng Phu (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cung Oán Ngâm Khúc, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Tự Tình Tiểu Luật (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Bần Nữ Thán (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Vịnh Bần Nữ Thán Thi (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Bài Hát Nam Ai (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Bài Hát Nam Thương (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cung Oán Ngâm Khúc, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Thanh Tâm Tài Nhân Thi Tập (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Xuân Tình Khúc Ca (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cung Oán Thi, Nôm (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Đại Nam Quốc Túy Quyển 1 & 2, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Việt Nam Phong Sử (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Tây Hành Nhật Trình Diễn Âm (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hải Dương Phong Vật Khúc, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Kim Văn Kiều Ca (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Hịch Đánh Quân Nhà Nguyễn, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Thế Tục Phú (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Hồng Nhan Bạc Phận Phú (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Gái Nhỡ Thì Phú (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Lắm Mối Tối Nằm Không Phú (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Mẹ Ơi Con Muốn Lấy Chống Phú (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Nữ Tử Hiếu Sĩ Từ Nông Phú (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Răn Cờ Bạc Phú (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Lê Triều Tướng Công Nguyễn Trãi Gia Huấn Ca, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Bài Văn Tế Ông Đại Tướng Vũ Công Tích và Ông Thượng Thư Ngô Tùng Chu (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Lưu Bình Dương Lễ Tân Truyện, Nôm, 2 copies (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lưu Bình Dương Lễ Tân Truyện, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Lưu Bình Dương Lễ Sự Tích Diễn Âm (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Lưu Bình Phú (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bài Hát Nam Ai (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bài Hát Nam Thương (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bài Hát Nam Bình (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Lưu Nguyễn Phổ Diễn Âm, all works in Nôm (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Nam Thiền Đệ Nhất Động Hành Trình Ngâm Khúc (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Nam Nữ Đối Ca, Nôm (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Nam Nữ Đối Ca Quyển 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Nam Nữ Đối Ca Quyển 2 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Nam Thiên Đệ Nhất Đôṇg Hành Trình Ngâm Khúc, all works in Nôm (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Hương Sơn Ca Khúc (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Thiếu Nữ Hoài Xuân Tình Thi (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Thiếu Nữ Hoài Xuân Tình Ca Khúc (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Khuyến Hiếu Diễn Âm Ca (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Bát Phản Diễn Âm Ca (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Ngũ Luân Thi Ca, all works in Nôm (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Tề Gia Ký (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Huấn Tử Quốc Âm Ca (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Khuyến Hiếu Ca (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Bát Phản Diễn Âm Ca (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Gia Huấn Truyện (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Nhị Độ Mai Tinh Tuyển Quyển 1, Nôm (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Nhị Độ Mai Tinh Tuyển Quyển 2, Nôm (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Nhị Độ Mai Tinh Tuyển Quyển 3, all works in Nôm (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Tì Bà Hành Diễn Âm Ca (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Nhị Độ Mai Tinh Tuyển, Nôm, 2 volumes (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Nhị Độ Mai Tinh Tuyển, all works in Nôm (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Gia Huấn Tử (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Âm Chất Văn Giải Âm (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Thu Dạ Ngâm Diễn Âm (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Nhị Thập Tứ Hiếu Diễn Ca, all works in Nôm (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Thái Thượng Cảm Ứng Thiên Quốc Âm Cả (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Lê Triều Nguyễn Tướng Công Gia Huấn Ca (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Nữ Tắc Diễn Ca, all works in Nôm (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Giáo Huấn Ca (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Nhân Vấn Nguyệt Đáp (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Lâm Tuyền Khách Phú (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Phan Trần Truyện Trùng Duyệt, Nôm, 2 notebooks (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Phật Thuyết Đại Thánh Mạt Kiếp Chân Kinh, all works in Nôm (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Huấn Tử Quốc Âm Ca (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Thái Thượng Cảm Ứng Thiên Quốc Âm Ca (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Phương Ngôn Phú, Nôm, 2 notebooks (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Phương Ngôn Tục Ngữ, Nôm, 2 notebooks (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Phương Ngôn Tục Ngữ, all works in Nôm (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Vấn Đáp Quốc Ngữ (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Ô Châu Cận Lục, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Ông Ninh Cổ Truyện, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Phạm Công Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Phỏng Thi Kinh Quốc Phong, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Phong Tình Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Quan Âm Chính Văn Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Trống Quan Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Quốc Âm Thư Mục, Hán and Nôm catalog (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Sãi Vãi, all works in Nôm (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Vịnh Kiều Tập Tự (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Bài Ca Tình Cảnh Nông Phu (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Bài Ca Vợ Khuyên Chồng (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Bài Hát Tứ Đai Cảnh (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Bài Hát Nam Thương (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Sứ Trình Tiện Lãm Khúc, all works in Nôm (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Tì Bà Hành Diễn Âm (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Tự Tình Hoài Xuân Khúc (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Tự Tình Ca Khúc (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Tây Du Truyện, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Tây Dương Liệt Phụ Truyện, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Chinh Phụ Ngâm Bị Lục, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Thánh Tổ Kệ Diễn Quốc Âm, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Thập Nhị Tiên Nàng Thỉnh Luyện Bí Pháp, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Thiên Nam Toàn Quốc Diễn Âm, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Tràng Hận Ca Diễn Âm,Nôm (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Thụ Dạ Lữ Hoài Ngâm Khúc, Hán with Diễn Nôm (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Bài Viếng Bạn, Hán with Diễn Ca Nôm (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Bài Của Cụ Tam Nguyên Yên Đổ, Nôm about Nguyễn Giặn Lại Cho Các Con (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Hương Sơn Nhật Trình, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Hoa Tình Khúc Diễn Ca, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Quan Âm Tống Tử Thư, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Tiến Sĩ Vũ Văn Tuấn Vinh Qui, Nôm (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Tiên Thánh Văn Tập, Nôm, 2 volumes (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Tống Trân Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Trinh Thứ Truyện, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Truyện Đổng Thiên Vương, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Hát Ả Đào, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Truyện Vua Lê Thai Tổ, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Truyện Vua Quang Trung, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Tứ Linh Truyện, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Từ Thức Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Lưu Nguyễn Nhập Thiên Thai Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Chức Cẩm Hồi Văn Diễn Âm, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Tục Ngạn Tập Biên, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Phương Ngôn Ngạn Ngữ, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Tướng Pháp Quốc Ngữ Ca, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Tử Vi Đẩu Số Tổng Luận Diễn Âm, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Âm Chất Văn Diễn Âm, Nôm, 3 volumes (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - An Lãng Chiêu Thuyền Tự Từ Đạo Hạnh Sự Tívh Thực Lục, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Bạch Vận Thi Tập, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Bích Câu Kỳ Ngộ, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Địa Tạng Bản Hành, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Dịch Chi Vi Qúy Tập, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Hà Ninh Tổng Đốc Chuyện, Nôm (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Hạnh Thục Ca, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Hảo Cầu Thục Nữ Tiểu Thuyết, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Hòa Bình Quan Lang Sử Lược Ca Âm, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Long Thành Cảnh Trí Ca, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Nam Xương Liệt Nữ Truyện, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Ngọc Hoa Cổ Tích Chuyện, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Nguyễn Đạt Nguyễn Sinh Tân Chuyện, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Nhị Thập Tứ Nữ Tắc Diễn Âm, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Phương Hoa Tân Chuyện, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Quốc Văn Tùng Ký, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Sãi Vãi, all works in Nôm (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Thi Hỏng Tự Cười Mình Phú Một Vần Yên Đổ Tam Nguyên (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Thi Hỏng Phú Một Vần Tú Tài Trần Kế Xương (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Thái Hòa Cảnh Tượng Chí Phạm Gia Huệ (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Thị Lựu Tự Tình (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Thăng Thiên Ca (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Tiên Thánh Văn Tập, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Thư Vị Văn Châu, Nôm (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Trận Vong Tướng Sĩ Văn, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - Văn Tế Phò Mã Vũ Tính Thượng Thư Ngô Tùng Chu, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Trống Quân Tân Chuyện Tam Thập Lục Chuyện, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Tì Bà Quốc Âm Tân Truyện, Preface in Hán, text in Nôm (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Vân Cát Thấn Nữ Cổ Lục Diễn Âm, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Văn Sách: Vấn Hăy Ăn Thời Béo, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Thượng Ngàn Công Chúa Văn, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Hòa Diệu Đại Vương Văn, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Thủy Tinh Công Chúa Văn, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Văn Trung Nguyệt Kính Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - Yên Đại Anh Thoại, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Vị Thành Giai Cú Tập Biên, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Chinh Phụ Ngâm Khúc, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Hoa Tình Khúc Diễn Âm Ca, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Vọng Phu, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Trống Quân Tân Chuyện, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Bưởm Hoa Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Ca Dao Ngạn Ngữ Phương Ngôn, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Ca Trù Thế Cách, AB 160 [Title matches another notebook, AB number listed to help differentiate], Nôm (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Ca Trù Thế Cách, AB 431 [Title matches another notebook, AB number listed to help differentiate], Nôm (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Ca Trù Thế Cách, AB 456 [Title matches another notebook, AB number listed to help differentiate], Nôm (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Chinh Phụ Ngâm, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Chúa Thao Cổ Chuyện, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Đông Tác Nguyễn Đại Vương Bản Truyện Giẫn Âm, Nôm with inserted Hán textual passages (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Hảo Cầu Tân Truyện, AB 134, Nôm (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Hảo Cầu Tân Truyện, AB 281, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Hồ Xuân Hương Thi Tập, AB 383, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Hồ Xuân Hương Thi Tập, AB 398, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Hoàng Trừu Truyện, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Hông Đức Quốc Âm Thi Tập, Nôm, 3 volumes (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Huấn Nữ Diễn Ca, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - Hương Sơn Quan Thế Âm Chân Kinh, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - Hương Sơn Quan Thế Âm Chân Kinh Tân Dịch, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - Khẩu Sử Ký, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Sĩ Phụ Ca Từ, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Vũ Sĩ Phụ Ca Từ, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Nông Gia Ca Từ, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Công Thương Tạp Ca, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Tình Chủng Dao, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Ca Dao Tùng Tập, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Sấm Ngữ Tập, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Ngạn Ngữ Tập, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Cân Kim Văn Tập, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Tạp Thuyết, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - Kinh Bắc Lạng Dật Sĩ Trần Ngôn, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - Điền Mê Khúc, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - [?] Khuất Ca, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Lâm Tuyền Kỳ Ngộ, Nôm (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Lê Triều Ngự Trế Quốc Âm Thi, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - Lê Triều Nguyễn Tướng Công Gia Huấn Ca, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Nam Hải Quan Âm Phật Sự Tích Ca, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Nguyệt Lịnh Quốc Âm Ca, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Nhật Tỉnh Ngâm, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - Phật Thuyết Đại Thánh Mạt Kiếp Chân Kinh, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 110)
  - Quan Âm Tống Tử Bản Hạnh, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 111)
  - Quế Sơn Tam Nguyên Thi Tập: Cai Lương Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 112)
  - Quốc Âm Diễn Thi: Cao Dao, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Quốc Văn Tùng Ký, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 114)
  - Quốc Văn Tùng Ký Quyển Hạ, AB 383, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 115)
  - Quốc Văn Tùng Ký Quyển Thượng, AB 383, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - Quốc Văn Tùng Ký Quyển Thượng, AB 383, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Hịch Đánh Quân Nguyên, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Trương Lưu Hầu Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Bài Tán Ông Tiến Sĩ, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Quách Tử Nghi Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Tụng Tây Hồ, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Phong Lưu Chuyện, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Chu Hồi Trở Phong Thán, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Tự Thuật, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Diễn Hạ Chung Nam Sơn Đề, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Khổng Tử Mộng Chu Công Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 117)
  - Quốc Văn Tùng Ký, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Thế Tục Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Mẹ Ơi Con Muốn Lấy Chồng, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Gái Nhỡ Thì Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Nữ Tử Hiếu Sĩ Từ Nông Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Vãng Chi Nhữ Gia Tất Kính Tất Giới Vô Vi Phu Tử, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Qúa Xuân Nữ Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Văn Sách: Bài Làm, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Lấm Mối Tối Nằm Không Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Chổng Mông Gào Chồng Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Mẹ Ơi Con Muốn Lấy Chồng Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Lẳng Lơ Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Thầy Đồ Giậy Học Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Đại Phú, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - Quốc Văn Tùng Ký: Tú Xương Thi Tập, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - Quốc Văn Tùng Ký: Yên Đổ Thi Tập, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Song Phung Kỳ Duyên, AB 399, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Song Phu Kỳ Duyên, AB 399, Nôm [Slightly different version] (Box 12, Folder 122)
  - Tiên Phả Dịch Lục, Nôm, 2 volumes (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - Thanh Tông Ngữ Vịnh Tử Thời Thi Tập, Nôm (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - Thừ Thức Tân Chuyện, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - Tuyên Phu Ngộ Phối Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - An Nam Phong Thổ Thoại (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - Bình Định Nam Giao Lục, Hán without Vietnamese transliteration (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - Chinh Phụ Ngâm, Hán (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - Lưu Bình Dương Lễ Sử Tích Diễn Âm, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Lưu Nguyễn Nhập Thiên Thai Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - Lý Công Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 132)
  - Mạc Sử Diễn Âm, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - Mai Đình Mộng Ký, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 134)
  - Mộng Hiền Truyện, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 135)
  - Nam Giao Kim Lý Hạng Ca Dao Chú Giải, Nôm, 3 volumes (Box 13, Folder 136)
  - Nam Mô Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 13, Folder 137)
  - Nam Sử Diễn Ca 5 vol., Nôm (Box 13, Folder 138)
  - Nhị Thập Tứ Trung Diễn Ca, Nôm [ Vietnamese transliteration unavailable pages 79-82 in copy 2], 2 copies (Box 13, Folder 139)
  - Nữ Lưu Tướng Truyện, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 140)
  - Nữ Tắc Diễn Âm, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 141)
  - Nữ Tú tài Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 142)
  - Phù Dung Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 143)
  - Phù Lục Trinh Quốc Công Phùng Thượng Thư Lưởng Gia Sấm Thuyết, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 144)
  - Phù Ủng Ca Qủy, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 145)
    - Hoàn Nguyên Ca Qủy, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 145)
    - Chảo Nha Ca Qủy, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 145)
  - Phương Hoa Bị Lục, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 146)
  - So Nghiêu Đối Thoại, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 147)
  - Quan Âm Chính Văn Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 148)
  - Văn Tiên Cổ Tích Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 149)
  - Tây Dương Quân Thiên Lạc, Nôm, 2 volumes (Box 14, Folder 150)
  - Thánh Du Quảng Huấn Diễn Nghĩa, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 151)
  - Tuyên Tỉnh Hành Trình Ngâm Khúc, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 152)
    - Vịnh An Bình Phong Cảnh, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Vân Trung Nguyệt Kính Tân Truyện, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - Hữu Kế Chuyện, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - Châu Sơ Kim Lục, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 155)
  - Nhuận Chính Trung Hiếu Tiết Nghĩa, Nôm (Box 14, Folder 156)
- Visual materials, Circa 1950-circa 1959; Series III
  This series contains black and white photographs (many duplicates), annotated in French and mounted on card stock, of China, Hong Kong, Vietnam, Laos, and Siam (Thailand), documenting ethnography and social life and customs in these areas, along with art and iconography. The principle focus appears to be the Hakka and Tanka people of Hong Kong. The photographs were reproduced from the collections of the École française d'Extrême-Orient. Location and category information is derived from information handwritten or stamped on card stock on which photographs are mounted. The series also includes two hand-inked maps, one of ancient Vietnam and the other of Tran Quoc Buddhist Temple, and sixteen color slides with Han and Nom characters in the background.
  - Hong Kong
    - Sampans and junks, street scenes, babies, waterfront, 41 photographs, 1956 October 1-21 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Acupuncture, 8 photographs, 1956 October 29 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Grain processing, squatters' children, 4 photographs, 1956 October 6 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Hennessy Road facades, 12 photographs, 1956 October 1-15 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Young Chinese women, 20 photographs, 1956 October 11-31 (Box 15, Folder 5)